

Passionate developer who thrives in collaborative environments, constantly striving for excellence.

## **Work Competences**

- Programming Languages:
   Java, C++, C#, Python,
   JavaScript
- Databases:

   SQL Server, Oracle,
   CosmoDB, MySQL,
   MongoDB
- Frameworks:
   React, Spring Boot, .Net,
   ASP.NET, WCF, Signal R
- Azure Cloud:

   IIS, DevOps, App Services,
   Azure Bot Services, VM
- Additional Knowledge: Networking, Active Directory

#### **LANGUAGES**

- Spanish: Native
- English: Advanced

## **CONTACT**

**Residence** San Francisco Dos Ríos, San José.

#### **Portfolio**

https://www.juniorricardoaf.site

#### LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/juni or-aburto-ferreto/

**E-mail** juniorricardoaf@gmail.com

**Phone** (+506) 7151 4989



# JUNIOR ABURTO FERRETO SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

**PROFILE** 

I am 25 years old and possess a strong focus in everything I do. I am highly interested in joining a company that fosters team growth and development. My vision is to stay actively involved with technology, ensuring that I am prepared in the best possible way to become an outstanding worker and developer.

Education

- Software Development Technician Cenfotec University (2019).
- Conversational English Idioma Internacional. (2018-2019).
- Software Development Engineering Cenfotec University (2019 2023)
- T4, Training for trainers Elev8 (2022)

Work Experience

# 2020-2022 Tek Experts

I initially joined as a Software Support Engineer and later advanced to the position of Technical Lead in the Web Applications team. I also served as a trainer for new team members, imparting my knowledge and expertise. I successfully trained 40 new company members across different hiring waves, contributing to their onboarding and the overall growth of the team. Consistently recognized as a top performer, underscoring my dedication, work ethic, and ability to consistently deliver outstanding results.

### 2022-2023 Microsoft

I was part of the WebApps US team. During my time there as a Software Support Engineer, I consistently performed well and helped both my team and Microsoft customers, particularly in addressing Azure and code-related issues. Additionally, I improved company processes and joined an internal organization to help Afro-American people in Costa Rica with fewer means.

#### 2023-2024 **Tek Experts**

I rejoined the company and secured the position of Technical Advisor, thanks to the extensive knowledge I had gained. Now, I contribute to the entire WebApps organization by assisting with cases, creating documentation, giving refreshers, and staying updated on various Microsoft technologies. I make difficult decisions with critical thinking that directly impact team performance, as I am the highest escalation point for over 20 engineers.

References

- Eng. Álvaro Cordero, Software Engineering, professor at Cenfotec University, 60474808.
- Eng. Pablo Monestel Gamboa, Head of web development, professor at Cenfotec University, 8719 5963.
- Oscar Mendoza, Team Manager at Tek Experts of DevOps/WebApps Team, 8990 7963
- Gary Ranne, Team Manager at Microsoft of WebApps US team, +1 (469) 7752632